<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./default.png" type="Source" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Silhouette Coefficient</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        This node computes the Silhouette Coefficient for the provided clustering result.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>This node computes the Silhouette Coefficient for the provided clustering result. Silhouette Coefficient is a useful metric for evaluating clustering performance. It is computed using (b - a) / max(a, b), where a is the mean inter-cluster distance and b is the mean intra-cluster distance from the closest cluster for each sample. The score can range from -1.0 to 1.0, while the higher the score, the better. There have to be at least two clusters for the score to be computed.</intro>
        
        
        <option name="Exlude">Columns to exclude from the computation.</option><option name="Include">Columns to include in the computation.</option>
    	<option name="Column with cluster names">The column that contains the name of the cluster for each point.</option>
    	<option name="Randomly sample a subset">If checked, a random subset will be sampled from the dataset. This is recommended for large datasets since computation is resource intensive.</option>
    	<option name="Size of the sample">The size of the sample as the proportion of the dataset. It can be in the range from 0.01 to 1.0, where 1.0 uses the whole dataset.</option>
    	<option name="Random seed">A random seed to be used when randomly sampling the data.</option>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Table with the data and clustering results">The table with the points and their cluster allocation as a separate column.</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Silhouette Coefficient">A table with one column that has one row containing the computed score. </outPort>
        
    </ports>
</knimeNode>
